Contact

rncolon1972@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/carloscolon-bsn-rn-cmsrn-0b9479103 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Care Spanish Customer Service

Languages

Spanish (Limited Working)
English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

BLS

CMSRN

Duolingo French Fluency: Beginner (Estimated)

Carlos Colon, BSN, RN, CMSRN

Staff Registered Nurse at Riverside Community Hospital Palm Springs, California

Summary

Professional, certified medical surgical oncology telemetry registered nurse (RN) with a diverse set of nursing skills, training and life experiences looks to provide high-quality, safe, culturally competent, evidence-based, and patient-centered care to individuals, families, communities, and populations in a variety of settings -- acute, long-term, ambulatory, or community. Desirous of positions that not only challenge me but also offer opportunities for professional development and advancement.

Experience

Riverside Community Hospital Staff Registered Nurse September 2019 - Present (11 months) Riverside

Provide quality, safe, patient-centered, and evidence-based direct care to adult populations who present with acute and/or chronic medical and mental problems using relationship care based- and nursing process models.

Educate patients, family, and caregivers to ensure effective self-management post discharge using evidence-based strategies.

Collaborate with interdisciplinary healthcare team to provide high quality care that involves patients and families.

Coordinate care for patients and their families as needed.

Maintain and develop professional personal growth through continued education and personal reflection.

Model professional leadership qualities to enhance teamwork and productivity.

Desert Regional Medical Center Telemetry Nurse August 2018 - May 2019 (10 months)

Palm Springs, California

Provide quality nursing care to patients who required varying levels of Acute Telemetry Care to manage acute coronary syndrome (ACS) and chest pain, acute on chronic or new onset heart failure with or without preserved ejection fraction, chronic atrial fibrillation (Afib) with rapid ventricular response or new onset Afib, syncopal episodes, acute deep venous thrombosis and/or pulmonary embolism, and electrolyte imbalances in the setting of dehydration, pneumonia, COPD exacerbation and diabetic acidosis.

University of Maryland Medical Center Clinical Nurse II September 2017 - July 2018 (11 months) Baltimore, Maryland

Continuously assessing 4-6 assigned adult clients and their families on busy 22-bed medical-surgical-telemetry inpatient unit to diagnose and manage actual/potential responses to acute and chronic physiological and psychosocial problems, using individualized nursing care plans that include direct care, counseling, education, care coordination and advocacy.

The George Washington University Hospital Staff Registered Nurse August 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 2 months) Washington D.C. Metro Area

Assess clients and their families on busy 60-bed inpatient acute medicalsurgical unit to treat and diagnose responses to acute and/or chronic physical or psychological conditions through direct care, advocacy, and care coordination.

Educate and counsel clients and their families to achieve better health outcomes post discharge

Collaborate with other health care professionals to provide quality, holistic and culturally competent care.

HCR ManorCare @ Mercy Fitzgerald Staff RN March 2016 - August 2016 (6 months) Yeadon, PA

Assess to treat and diagnose clients' and families' actual or potential responses to subacute and chronic physiological and psychological health problems using proven assessment tools and good communication skills.

Plan, implement, and evaluate care plans that are tailored to my clients' individualized needs, as well as culturally appropriate.

Document all nursing activities and changes in clients' condition.

Communicate all clients' and families' concerns to the appropriate interdisciplinary team member and document accordingly

Provide client and family education when needed.

Admit and discharge clients from the unit on a daily basis.

Apply therapeutic communication with clients and their families to establish therapeutic relationships that promote positive health outcomes.

Evaluate and self-reflect on all nursing activities in order to improve my quality of care.

Provide culturally sensitive psychosocial support to all clients' and their families.

PrimeCare Medical, Inc.
Registered Nurse
August 2015 - March 2016 (8 months)

Chester and Bucks counties

Quality nursing care for inmates at Bucks Co Correctional Facility. Treat inmates' responses to actual and/or potential emergency, acute or chronic medical conditions. Collaborate with mental health and medical team members daily to ensure the inmates receive quality healthcare to which they are entitled during incarceration.

Einstein Healthcare Network
Patient Care Associate
November 2014 - February 2015 (4 months)
East Norriton, PA

Provided assistance to RNs with basic nursing care, such as feeding, toileting, positioning, vital signs, ECGs, and weight. Restocked unit as needed. Collaborated with other team members to ensure client safety and comfort. Regarded as pleasant and competent by staff and clients.

Education

Maryville University of Saint Louis

Master of Science - MS, Nursing - Adult-Gerontology Primary Care Nurse

Practitioner (AGPCNP) · (2019 - 2022)

Ohio University

BSN, summa cum laude, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2015 - 2016)

Bucks County Community College
Associate of Arts (A.A.), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2010 - 2015)

City University of New York-Brooklyn College
Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), cum laude, Cinematography and Film/Video
Production · (2000 - 2003)